rolanddga.com 2018-10-12

# Privacy Statement | Roland

## Our Commitment to Privacy

**Introduction.**

Roland DGA Corporation recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of all personal information provided by its customers, including users of [www.rolanddga.com](http://www.rolanddga.com/), [www.rolanddgastore.com](http://www.rolanddgastore.com/) and other Roland DGA affiliated websites (collectively "Roland Sites"). We created the following policy guidelines with a fundamental respect for our customers´ right to privacy and because we value our relationships with our customers. Your visit to the Roland Sites is subject to this Privacy Statement and our Online Terms and Conditions. 

**Description.**

This Privacy Statement describes the types of information we collect  how we may use that information and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Statement also describes the measures we take to protect the security of this information as well as how you may reach us to update your contact information, remove your name from our marketing lists or ask us any questions you may have about our use of your personal information. It also explains how you may elect to stop receiving communications about our products and services. 

**Applicability.**

If you visit other regional websites for Roland affiliates, or link to another website from this Site, you are subject to the privacy policy applicable for that website and we suggest that you consult such privacy policy.

### Data Collection 

**Personal Data Collected Directly From Visitors.**

Roland DGA collects personal information when: you purchase our products; you submit questions or comments to us; you request information or materials; you request warranty or post-warranty service and support; you register products; you participate in surveys; you participate in promotions, premiums, sweepstakes or contests; you apply for employment; and by other means that may be specifically provided for on the Roland Sites or in our correspondence with you. 

**Type of Personal Data.**

The type of information collected directly from the user may include your name, your company's name, physical contact information, address, billing and delivery information, e-mail address, credit card information, the products you use, your local dealer, demographic information such as your age, gender, preferences, and interests and information relating to the sale or installation of your product. 

**Non-Personal Data Collected Automatically.**

We may collect information about your interaction with Roland Sites and services. For example, we may use website analytics tools on our site to retrieve information from your browser, including the site you came from, the search engine(s) and the keywords you used to find our site, the pages you view within our site, and your browser add-ons. We may also use technologies, such as cookies and web beacons, to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on our sites and services. The cookies allow us to recognize you when you return to the Site and to provide you with a customized experience that we feel will be of value to you. Additionally, we collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type, capabilities and language, your operating system, access times and referring Web site addresses.

**Storage and Processing.**

Personal data collected on our websites may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Roland DGA or its affiliates, joint ventures, or third party servicers maintain facilities.

### How We Use the Data

**Services and transactions.  **

We use your personal data to deliver services or execute transactions you request, such as providing information about Roland DGA products and services, processing orders, answering customer service requests, facilitating use of our Web sites, enabling online shopping, and so forth. In order to offer you a more consistent experience in interacting with Roland DGA, information collected by our websites may be combined with information we collect by other means. We use your personal data to carry out our obligations and enforce our rights arising from any contracts or other transactions entered into between you and us, including for billing and collection.

**Product Development.  **

We use the personal and non-personal data for product development, including for such processes as idea generation, product design and improvements, detail engineering, market research and marketing analysis.

**Website Improvement.  **

We may use the personal and non-personal data to improve our websites (including our security measures) and related products or services, or to make our websites easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information or by customizing our websites to your particular preference or interests.

**Marketing Communications.  **

We may use your personal data to inform you of products or services available from Roland DGA. When collecting information that might be used to contact you about our products and services, we often give you the opportunity to opt-out from receiving such communications. Moreover, in our email communications with you we  may include an unsubscribe link allowing you to stop delivery of that type of communication. If you elect to unsubscribe, we will remove you from the relevant list within 15 business days.

**Employment.   **

If you provide personal information to us with respect to employment, such as your resume, we will treat such personal information as confidential and may use it only to consider you for current and future employment opportunities.

### Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose aggregated information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, without restriction.

We may disclose personal information that we collect or you provide as described in this privacy policy to:

**Subsidiaries and affiliates.**

Roland shares customer information, including personal information, within our family of companies, including our subsidiaries and affiliates.

**Authorized Roland Dealers**

Roland sells many of its products through a network of independent dealers. When you inquire about any of our products, request a brochure or white paper, request technical support or make similar inquiries we may send your personal information to our Roland Authorized Dealers who serve your geographical area. When you purchase any products from Roland DGA's online store, information regarding your purchases may be shared with our Roland Authorized Dealers who serve your geographical area.

Roland Authorized Dealers receiving your personal information may follow up with you regarding your inquiries and requests and may also explore with you sales opportunities for other Roland products that may be of interest to you.

**Authorized Roland Servicers.  **

Roland may provide services to customers, either in or out of warranty, through authorized Roland servicers.  When you request technical support, warranty service, out-of-warranty service or make similar inquiries we may send your personal information to our Roland Authorized Servicers who serve your geographical area.  

Roland Authorized Dealers receiving your personal information may follow up with you regarding your inquiries and requests and may also explore with you sales opportunities for other Roland products that may be of interest to you.

**Service Providers.  **

We may retain other companies and individuals to perform functions on our behalf consistent with this Online Privacy Statement. Examples include credit card processors, data analysis firms, customer support specialists, email vendors, webhosting companies, information services consultants/vendors and fulfillment companies. Such third parties may be provided with access to personal information needed to perform their functions but may not use such information other than on our behalf and in accordance with this Online Privacy Statement.

****Co-Sponsors and Other Third Parties.  ****

In some instances, you may be offered the opportunity to opt out or consent to the sharing of your information with a third party such as an event or promotion co-sponsor. If you consent or do not opt out, we will share your information with such third party and the information you provide may be used by such third party for their own purposes and in accordance with their own policies. **  
**

**Successors.  **

Circumstances may arise where for strategic or other business reasons Roland DGA decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize particular businesses. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal data to prospective or actual purchasers, or receiving it from sellers. It is Roland DGA's practice to seek appropriate protection for information in these types of transactions.

**Compliance With Law and Other Protections.  **

Roland DGA reserves the right to disclose the information it collects if Roland DGA believes that such disclosure is necessary to comply with applicable law or legal process, to avoid liability for Roland DGA and/or its affiliates, agents and partners, to enforce our apply our terms of use, or terms of sale and other agreements, including for billing and collection purposes, and/or to protect the rights and property (including intellectual property) of Roland DGA and others, including Roland DGA's affiliates, agents, partners and customers. Further, Roland DGA may disclose the information it collects if Roland DGA suspects that an individual or entity has provided fraudulent or illegal information, has committed an illegal, fraudulent or wrongful act or omission, has attempted to pose as someone else, or has attempted an unauthorized use or access of any computer system or website.

###  Commitment to Data Security 

**Security.**

Roland DGA Corporation uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure your personal information. For example, we store sensitive personal data on computer systems with limited access that are located in facilities to which access is limited. When you move around a site to which you have logged in, or from one site to another that uses the same login mechanism, we verify your identity by means of an encrypted cookie placed on your machine. When you place an order with us, view account information, or provide financial information, we protect the transmission of such data using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption.  Nonetheless, Roland DGA Corporation does not guarantee the security, accuracy or completeness of any such information or procedures.

**Passwords.**

For sites to which you login, it is your responsibility to ensure the security of your password and not to reveal this information to others. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always logout before leaving a website so that subsequent users will not be able to access your data. 

**Bulletin Boards, Chat Rooms and Forums.**

Some of our sites may enable you to participate in public services such as discussion boards, chats, and live events.  Please use discretion when providing personal information about yourself when using these services.  Be aware that when you disclose personal information at these sites, the information may be collected and used by others to send unsolicited messages.  These services are open to the public, and what you post there can be seen by anyone and is not protected.  Roland DGA cannot control the comments that you may receive while you participate in these services.  You may find other people's comments to be offensive, harmful or inaccurate.  Roland DGA is not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

**Internet.**

The transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information transmitted to our Website. Any transmission of personal information is at your own risk. We are not responsible for circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures contained on the Roland Sites.

### Commitment to Children's Privacy 

**Minors.**

The Roland Sites are not directed to minors, especially those children under the age of thirteen (13), and we do not knowingly collect personal information from minors on the Roland Sites. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a minor on the Roland Sites, we will delete the information from our records. 

### Your Privacy Rights 

**How You Can Correct Your Information**

To change or update your personal information please send a "remove" email to Privacy[at]rolanddga.com and re-register with the new information.  For users of Roland's online store (www.rolanddgastore.com), you may change or update your information by logging into your account. 

### How You Can Opt Out

In most cases, we provide you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information.  For example, if you request information regarding a product/service but do not wish to receive any additional marketing material from us, you can indicate your preference on the request form. Likewise, when setting up your account in Roland's online store (www.rolanddgastore.com), you can "opt out" of having certain personal information sent to your local dealer. 

If you no longer wish to receive any of our various marketing communications, you may choose to opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at Privacy@rolanddga.com.

Of course, you can always decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case Roland DGA may not be able to provide those services to you.

**Contact Us**

If you have questions regarding this privacy statement, our handling of your personal data, or your privacy rights under applicable law, including California Civil Code Section 1798.83, please contact us by mail at the address below.

**Roland DGA Corporation**  
Attn: General Counsel  
15363 Barranca Parkway  
Irvine, CA 92618

### Statement Updates

**Revisions.**

Roland DGA reserves the right to modify this privacy statement from time to time. If we decide to change our Privacy Statement, we will post the revised Statement here. We suggest that you periodically consult this Privacy Statement.

**Date.**

This Privacy Statement was last amended on January 30, 2017.
